Guide to the Time Inc. Time Editorial Records 1938-2009 MS 3009-RG 7
New-York Historical Society
Time Inc. Time Editorial Records
1938-2009 (bulk 1938-1998)
New-York Historical Society
Time, inc.
MS 3009-RG 7
102 Linear feet in 100 record cartons, 1 flat box, and 1 microfilm box including 8 reels of microfilm
The Time Editorial Records contain records from offices and staff from the editorial side of the magazine, not the publishing or business side. Staff represented include managing editors, executive editors, a cover researcher, a senior design coordinator, and a journalist.
Arrangement
Organized into six series based on hierarchy of office and job titles and then chronologically by office holder when applicable:
Series I. Managing Editor Files
Series II. Executive Editor Files
Series III. Art Department Records
Series IV. Rosalind Constable Reports
Series V. Letters Department Records
Series VI. Elections Research
Biographical / Historical
For the majority of Time Inc.'s existence, the company maintained a strict separation of editorial from the publishing and business side of each magazine, colloquially called the separation of "church" (editorial) and "state" (publishing). Editorial includes the editors, researchers, and art department. The editorial side reported up to the editor-in-chief and the publishing/business side reported up to the corporate business executive which was the president prior to 1960 and the chief executive officer after. Henry Luce structured Time Inc. this way so that the business side could not (in theory) influence the editorial content of the publications. For example, the advertising sales people could not interfere with a magazine's decision to run an article on the dangers of cigarette smoking, even though it might mean losing millions of dollars in tobacco ads.
Time is the first magazine created by Time Inc. with the first issue published on March 3, 1923. Time Inc. cofounders Henry R. Luce and Briton Hadden shared the masthead as Editors until Hadden's death in 1929. At this time, John S. Martin became the first Managing Editor of Time with Luce still over him as Editor.
According to Time Inc., Time pioneered the news magazine, at least the modern news magazine. Time's format of short articles summarizing news events and other items of interest and importance became the standard for later news magazines. Magazine sections included national and international affairs, business, education, science, medicine, law, religion, sports, books, and the arts.
Time published several foreign-language editions, the first launched in 1941 delivered by air service to Latin America; special issues including the popular Time Person of the Year (formerly Man of the Year); and Time for Kids, a children's magazine.
Citations:
Elson, Robert T. 1968. Time Inc.: The Intimate History of a Publishing Enterprise, 1923-1941. New York: Atheneum.
The Editors of Encyclopaedia Britannica. "Time," Encyclopaedia Britannica. Encyclopaedia Britannica, Inc., 2018. https://www.britannica.com/topic/Time-American-magazine.
Hooper, Bill. Email to Holly Deakyne, 10 June 2016.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers with the exception of restricted materials. Restricted materials may include personnel records; contracts and agreements; and records with personally identifiable information. Restricted materials are located in boxes 2459 to 2463 and R39. Materials created within the past 35 years also may be subject to restriction on a case-by-case basis. Unreformatted audiovisual and digital material in the collection is not accessible. Except for microfilm, materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use.
Related Archival Materials Note
This finding aid relates to just one record group of the Time Inc. Records. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the Guide to the Time Inc. Records (MS 3009). The Henry Luce Papers (MS 3014) were acquired with the Time Inc. Records. The collection of books acquired with the records are cataloged as the Time Inc. Reference Library. For additional records on Time Editorial, see the Guide to the Time Inc. Subject Files (MS 3009-RG 1).
Scope and Contents
The Time Editorial Records contain records from offices and staff from the editorial side of the magazine, not the publishing or business side. Staff represented include Managing Editors Otto Fuerbringer and James R. Gaines, Executive Editors Dana Tasker, Edward Jamieson and Joëlle Attinger, Art Department Cover Researcher Rosemary Frank, Art Department Senior Design Coordinator Linda Freeman, and art and culture journalist Rosalind Constable. Records include internal and external correspondence; departmental and subject files; cover artist files; speeches; travel itineraries; personnel files; files and reports from the Letters Department; and collected research for elections reporting.
Provenance
Gift of Time Inc. in 2015.
Art -- Publications -- Periodicals; Corporation records; Corporations -- History; Corporations -- New York (State) -- New York.; Editors -- New York (State) -- New York; Elections -- United States.; Journalists -- United States; Organization files; Public opinion polls -- United States.; Publishers and publishing -- New York (State) -- New York.; Women journalists –- New York (State) -– New York; Constable, Rosalind; Frank, Rosemary; Fuerbringer, Otto, 1910-2008; Gaines, James R.; Jamieson, Edward, 1929-2018; Tasker, J. Dana, 1904-1975; Yankelovich, Skelly and White, inc.; Time, inc. -- Archives; Time, inc. -- History
- Series I.A. Managing Editor Otto Fuerbringer Files, 1939-1985 (bulk 1950-1974); 15 Linear feet in 16 record cartons
  Biographical/Historical Note
  Otto Fuerbringer started as a writer for Time in 1942 after working at the St. Louis Post Dispatch. He served as a senior editor and assistant managing editor, and was promoted to managing editor in 1960. Fuerbringer held this title until May 1968 when Hedley Donovan appointed him as the "chief explorer of Time Inc.'s interests and opportunities in the newspaper field," making him a vice president. This appointment morphed into being the managing editor for the Magazine Development Group. While head of this group, Time Inc. created and first published Money and People. Fuerbringer retired from Time Inc. in September 1973.
  Citations:
  "Retire? Never." FYI, September 29, 1975.
  Scope and Contents Note
  While the Otto Fuerbringer Files span his career at Time Inc., the majority of the files date from his role as assistant managing editor and managing editor of Time. Subject Files include material specifically from his work as managing editor of the Magazine Development Group, and some speeches have later dates. These files do not include Fuerbringer's corporate work researching newspapers for Time Inc.
  Arrangement
  Organized into five subseries:
  Subseries I.A.1. Correspondence and Memoranda
  Subseries I.A.2. Subject Files
  Subseries I.A.3. Newstours
  Subseries I.A.4. Speeches
  Subseries I.A.5. Trips
  - Subseries I.A.1. Correspondence and Memoranda, 1939-1968; 4.5 Linear feet in 5 record cartons
    The Correspondence and Memoranda files were partially processed by the Time Inc. Archives producing the correspondence files titled: Adler, Biographical, Burck, Congratulatory, Pace, Personal, Reese, Time Edit, Toss(?), and parts of General. Some of these files state that they are "from correspondence." Materials remaining in the unprocessed General files are similar to materials found throughout the files created by the Time Inc. Archives which may mean the processing was incomplete.
    General includes letters from subjects of Time covers (Barbara Streisand and an assistant to Martin Luther King, Jr.); invitations to events and to speak; from various companies including Ford Motor Company; and from social organizations (Harvard Club of New York). Biographical contains personal correspondence, letters from school acquaintances, and a 1939 article on Fuerbringer from St. Louis Post Dispatch. Frank Shea was the assistant to the managing editor, and his correspondence primarily contains responses to readers on the behalf of Bernard Auer, Roy Alexander, Fuerbringer during their absences. Toss(?) looks like material weeded out by the Time Inc. archivist for deaccessioning. Personal contains letters to and from family, Harvard Club of New York, and former St. Louis colleagues regarding social events, participation on boards, personal charitable activity, and the handling personal household tasks.
    Other items of interest include an information packet and letter from Ford thanking Fuerbringer for visiting to test drive the upcoming 1964 Ford Mustang; a 1965 letter from Time writer Henry Grunwald, the future Editor-in-Chief, requesting visas to travel for work.
    Arrangement Note
    Organized alphabetically with general correspondence at the front.
    - Correspondence: General, 1950-1965 (Offsite-box 1211, Folder 1-11)
    - Correspondence: General, 1966-1967 (Offsite-box 2682)
    - Correspondence: General, 1968 (Offsite-box 2683, Folder 1-5)
    - Correspondence: Adler, Mortimer J., 1951-1965 (Offsite-box 1211, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence: Biographical, 1939-1965 (Offsite-box 1211, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: Burck, Jacob, 1961 (Offsite-box 1211, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence: Congratulatory, 1951-1961 (Offsite-box 1211, Folder 15-16)
    - Correspondence: Manning, Robert, 1958-1960 (Offsite-box 1211, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence: Marked for Refiling, 1957-1966 (Offsite-box 1211, Folder 18)
      Includes correspondence and other materials removed from correspondence files by the Time Inc. Archives and marked with sticky notes to be refiled. The intended location for refiling is unknown.
    - Correspondence: Pace, Frank R., 1963 (Offsite-box 1211, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence: Personal, 1948-1965 (Offsite-box 1211, Folder 20-24)
    - Correspondence: Reese, Benjamin H., 1951-1953 (Offsite-box 1212, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Shea, Frank, 1965-1967 (Offsite-box 1212, Folder 2-11)
    - Correspondence: Speeches, 1950-1964 (Offsite-box 1212, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence: Time Edit, 1950-1965 (Offsite-box 1212)
    - Correspondence: Time Edit, 1950-1965 (Offsite-box 1213, Folder 1-7)
    - Correspondence: Toss (?), 1949-1965 (Offsite-box 1213, Folder 8-13)
    - Correspondence: Vice President Appointment, 1968 (Offsite-box 1213, Folder 14-15)
    - Memoranda: Donovan, Hedley, 1964 (Offsite-box 1213, Folder 16)
    - Memoranda: Donovan, Hedley and Henry Luce, 1966-1967 (Offsite-box 1213, Folder 17-18)
    - Memoranda: From Fuerbringer, 1956-1958 (Offsite-box 1213, Folder 19)
    - Memoranda: Fuerbringer and Time Staff, 1949-1968 (Offsite-box 1213)
    - Memoranda: Fuerbringer and Time Staff, 1949-1968 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 1-2)
    - Memoranda: Luce, Henry, 1960-1966 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 3-5)
  - Subseries I.A.2. Subject Files, 1948-1985; 9 Linear feet in 10 record cartons
    Although only some folders have "Time" in the title, the majority of Fuerbringer's Departmental Files relate to Time and his work as the managing editor.
    Organized alphabetically.
    - Adenauer, Konrad: Interview, 1962 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 6)
    - Australian Edition, 1965 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 7)
    - Bonus Letters, 1960-1975 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 8)
    - Book: One Day in the Life of America, 1975 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 9)
    - Books Magazine, 1973 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 10)
    - Budgets, 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 11)
    - Canada, 1960-1962 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 12-13)
    - Canada Convention, 1963 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 14)
    - Canada Transfer, 1961 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 15)
    - Cerf, Ed: Senior Editor, 1956-1957 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 16)
    - Cerf, Ed: Senior Editor [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R39)
    - Closing: Early / Saturday, 1958-1960 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 17)
    - Closing: Monday-Friday, 1966 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 18)
    - Color Projects, 1960-1964 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 19)
    - Company Policy, 1948-1957 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 20)
    - Conflict of Interest, 1961 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 21)
    - Covers: Divorce, 1963 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 22)
    - Covers: God, undated (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 23)
    - Covers: London, 1966 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 24)
    - Covers: Jeanne Moreau, 1967 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 25)
    - Covers: Puritan, 1962 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 26)
    - Covers: Thailand, 1965 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 27)
    - Covers: Harold Wilson, 1965 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 28)
    - Culligan, Joe, 1966 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 29)
    - Daily Newspaper, 1970 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 30)
    - Donovan, Hedley: Speeches, 1965-1968 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 31)
    - Edit Close Costs, 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 32)
    - Errors Report, 1966 (Offsite-box 2683, Folder 6)
    - Food Magazine, undated (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 33)
    - French Election, 1966 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 34)
    - FYI 25th Anniversary Issue, 1960-1961 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 35)
    - Gourmet, 1973 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 36)
    - Harvard Club of New York City, 1952-1956 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 37)
    - Israel, 1973 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 38)
    - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1964-1968 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 39)
    - Kennedy, John F., undated (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 40)
    - Kennedy, Robert, 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 41)
    - Keogh, Jim, 1958-1960 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 42)
    - Legal Matters, 1961-1967 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 43)
    - Legal: Wasserman vs. Time Inc., 1967 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 44)
    - Letters Department, 1966 (Offsite-box 1255, Folder 45)
    - Life: Bicentennial, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 1256, Folder 1)
    - Life: Dummy, 1974 (Offsite-box 1256, Folder 2)
    - Life: Memoranda, 1973-1975 (Offsite-box 1256, Folder 3)
    - Life: Monthly, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 1256, Folder 4)
    - Life: The New Life, 1960 (Offsite-box 1256, Folder 5)
    - Life: Old, 1969-1971 (Offsite-box 1256, Folder 6-7)
      While it is not clear what is meant by the title "Old," these files do not relate to the old Life humor magazine. Contents include evaluations of Life and might be Fuerbringer's old files on Life or mean Life prior to the 1972 shut down.
    - Life: One Day in America, 1971-1974 (Offsite-box 1256, Folder 8)
    - Life: One Shots, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 1256, Folder 9)
    - Life: Quarterly, 1974 (Offsite-box 1256, Folder 10)
    - Life: Watergate, 1972-1973 (Offsite-box 1256, Folder 11)
    - Life: Year End Issue, 1973 (Offsite-box 1256, Folder 12)
    - Life: Year in Pictures, 1974 (Offsite-box 1256, Folder 13)
    - Luce, Clare Boothe, 1956 (Offsite-box 1256, Folder 14)
    - Luce, Henry: Autobiography, approximately 1968 (Offsite-box 1256, Folder 15)
    - Luce, Henry: Death, 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 1256, Folder 16-17)
    - Luce, Henry: Obituary, 1967 (Offsite-box 1256, Folder 18-19)
    - Luce, Henry: Resignation, 1964 (Offsite-box 1256, Folder 20)
    - Luce, Henry: Story in Der Spiegel, 1961 (Offsite-box 1256, Folder 21)
    - Luce, Henry: Will, 1965 (Offsite-box 1256, Folder 22)
    - The Lutheran, 1963 (Offsite-box 1256, Folder 23)
    - Magazines, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 1256, Folder 24)
    - Magazine Development: Camera Month, undated (Offsite-box 1256)
    - Magazine Development: Camera Month, undated (Offsite-box 1257, Folder 1)
    - Magazine Development: Camera Month: Brochures, 1972 (Offsite-box 2683, Folder 7)
    - Magazine Development: Camera Month: Chronology of Memos, 1971-1973 (Offsite-box 2683, Folder 8)
    - Magazine Development: Camera Month: Dummy, 1973? (Offsite-box 2776, Folder 1)
    - Magazine Development: Camera Month: Prospectus, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 2683, Folder 9)
    - Magazine Development: Cassette Tape, undated (Offsite-box 1257, Folder 2)
      Includes audiovisual material.
      1 audiocassette (Sony C-90): analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape.
    - Magazine Development: Fortune, 1983 (Offsite-box 2683, Folder 10)
    - Magazine Development: Leisure, 1984-1985 (Offsite-box 2683, Folder 11)
    - Magazine Development: Life, undated (Offsite-box 1257, Folder 3-4)
    - Magazine Development: Money: Brochures, 1972? (Offsite-box 2683, Folder 12)
    - Magazine Development: Money: Contents and Memoranda Regarding First Issues, 1971-1975 (Offsite-box 2683, Folder 13-14)
    - Magazine Development: Money: Press Clippings, 1971-1973 (Offsite-box 2683, Folder 15)
    - Magazine Development: Money: Prospectus, 1971 (Offsite-box 2684, Folder 1)
    - Magazine Development: People, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 2684, Folder 2)
    - Magazine Development: People: Dummies, 1973 (Offsite-box 2684, Folder 3)
    - Magazine Development: People: Early Issues, 1973-1975 (Offsite-box 2684, Folder 4-5)
    - Magazine Development: People: Memoranda and Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Offsite-box 2684, Folder 6-8)
    - Magazine Development: People: Name Search, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 2684, Folder 9)
    - Magazine Development: People: Prospectus, 1973 (Offsite-box 2684, Folder 10-12)
    - Magazine Development: People: Prospectus and Memos, 1973 (Offsite-box 2684, Folder 13)
    - Magazine Development: People: Reactions, 1973-1975 (Offsite-box 2684, Folder 14)
    - Magazine Development: People: Staff and Budget, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 2684, Folder 15)
    - Magazine Development: People: Story Suggestions, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 2684, Folder 16)
    - Magazine Development: People: Title and Start Up, 1973 (Offsite-box 2684, Folder 17)
    - Magazine Development: People: Title and Start Up, 1973 (Offsite-box 2775, Folder 1)
    - Magazine Development: Slides, undated (Offsite-box 1257, Folder 5)
    - Magazine Development: View: General, undated (Offsite-box 1257, Folder 6-8)
    - Magazine Development: View: Dummy, undated (Offsite-box 2776, Folder 2)
    - Magazine Development: Well: Brochures, 1971? (Offsite-box 2775, Folder 2)
    - Magazine Development: Well: Correspondence and Memoranda, 1971 (Offsite-box 2775, Folder 3)
    - Magazine Development: Well: Dummy, 1971? (Offsite-box 2776, Folder 3)
    - Magazine Development: Well: Prospectus, 1971 (Offsite-box 2775, Folder 4)
    - Magazine Development: Women's Magazine: General, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 2775, Folder 5-6)
    - Magazine Development: Women's Magazine: Prospectus, 1975 (Offsite-box 2775, Folder 7)
    - Minnesota Symposium on Visual Communication, 1974 (Offsite-box 1257, Folder 9)
    - Modern Living, 1961 (Offsite-box 1257, Folder 10)
    - Movie, 1971 (Offsite-box 1257, Folder 11-13)
    - New Magazine Suggestions, 1971-1975 (Offsite-box 1257-1258)
    - Newsletter, 1971 (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 2)
    - Newspapers, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 2775, Folder 8)
    - Newspapers: Daily: Chicago Suburbs, 1968-1970 (Offsite-box 2775, Folder 9)
    - News Service: General, 1962 (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 3)
    - News Service: Clurman, Richard, 1965 (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 4)
    - News Service: Epstein, Rose, 1966-1967 (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 5)
    - Newsstand Sales, 1965-1968 (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 6)
    - The New York Times, 1966 (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 7)
    - On the Mall, 1972-1973 (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 8)
    - Philosophy: Adler Essay, 1965 (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 9)
    - Pioneer Press, 1972 (Offsite-box 2775, Folder 10)
    - Portraiture Brochure, 1965 (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 10)
    - Possible Staff Members: Writers, 1958 (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 11)
    - Postal Hearings, 1957-1960 (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 12)
    - Presidential Election, 1959-1964 (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 13-14)
    - Progressive Farmer, 1974 (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 15)
    - Publisher's Letter, 1948-1954 (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 16)
    - Purtell, Joe, 1962-1963 (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 17)
    - Quality, 1982-1984 (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 18)
    - Redbook, 1974 (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 19)
    - Religion Magazine, 1969-1973 (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 20-21)
    - Reprint / Syndication, 1964-1965 (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 22)
    - Retirement, 1973-1975 (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 23-24)
    - Roper Research Polls, 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 25)
    - Sea Spray Editorial Meeting, 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 26-28)
      According to a memoranda, this multi-day retreat is the "first of its kind" for Time. The records include a full transcript of the initial session and Donovan Hedley's remarks.
    - Section: Books, 1964 (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 29)
    - Section: Essay - Prospectus, 1965 (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 30-31)
    - Section: Law, 1963 (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 32)
    - Section: New Business, undated (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 33)
    - Section: Opinion, 1953 (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 34)
    - Section: Personality, 1952-1953 (Offsite-box 1258, Folder 35)
    - Show Business, 1958 (Offsite-box 1259, Folder 1)
    - Southeast Asia: Grunwald, Henry, 1964 (Offsite-box 1259, Folder 2)
    - Southern Living, 1974 (Offsite-box 1259, Folder 3)
    - Story List Memoranda to Henry Luce and Fuerbringer, 1956-1957 (Offsite-box 1259, Folder 4)
    - Style Memoranda, undated (Offsite-box 1259, Folder 5)
    - Time: General, 1957-1958 (Offsite-box 1259, Folder 6)
    - Time: After May 1968 (Offsite-box 1259, Folder 7)
    - Time: Changes, 1960-1962 (Offsite-box 1259, Folder 8)
    - Time: Comments On, 1960-1968 (Offsite-box 1259, Folder 9-10)
    - Time: German Dummy, 1967 (Offsite-box 1259, Folder 11)
    - Time: Improvement Of, 1962 (Offsite-box 1259, Folder 12)
    - Time: Personnel, 1947-1962 (Offsite-box 1259, Folder 13-17)
    - Time: Personnel [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R39)
    - Time: Prospectus and History, 1944-1963 (Offsite-box 1259, Folder 18)
    - Time: Stories About, 1958 (Offsite-box 1259, Folder 19)
    - Time: Style Criticism, 1668-1966 (Offsite-box 1259, Folder 20)
    - Time: Translated Editions, undated (Offsite-box 1259, Folder 21)
    - Time: Type Change, 1960 (Offsite-box 1259, Folder 22)
    - Time Life International Printing Plants: Bob Boyd Report, 1963 (Offsite-box 1259, Folder 23)
    - TV Program, undated (Offsite-box 1259, Folder 24)
    - Unsolicited Manuscripts, 1961 (Offsite-box 1259, Folder 25)
    - Vietnam: Comments File, 1967 (Offsite-box 1259, Folder 26)
    - Vietnam: Correspondents Controversy, 1963-1965 (Offsite-box 1259, Folder 27)
    - View: General, 1972-1973 (Offsite-box 1259-1260)
    - View: Ideas, 1972-1973 (Offsite-box 1260, Folder 2)
    - Vishniak, Mark: Memoranda, 1962 (Offsite-box 1260, Folder 3)
    - Washington Memoranda, 1965 (Offsite-box 1260, Folder 4)
    - Westmoreland, William: Man of the Year, 1965 (Offsite-box 1260, Folder 5)
    - Women's Magazine: General, 1973-1975 (Offsite-box 1260, Folder 6-8)
    - Women's Magazine: Patricia Ryan Interviews, 1974 (Offsite-box 1260, Folder 9-10)
    - Women's Wear Daily Article on Time vs. Newsweek, 1968 (Offsite-box 1260, Folder 11)
  - Subseries I.A.3. Newstours, 1963-1965; 0.5 Linear feet in 1 record carton
    While title on these early materials call it a "news tour," later articles and other publications written by Time and Time Inc. employees cement the term "Newstour." According to a packet on the history of Time Newstours in Henry Grunwald's files, "the purpose of the Newstour is to give an opportunity to a small group of American leaders to visit areas of the world currently in the news..." While the Newstour is arranged by Time, each participant pays their own expenses. Newstours includes briefing binders containing itineraries, participant lists, and background information; cables, memoranda, and other correspondence; and notes and other travelogues written by Fuerbringer and other participants.
    Organized chronologically.
    - 1963: Time News Tour of Europe (Offsite-box 1260, Folder 12-14)